你好，这些漂亮的人，走进这个视频，所有关于Linux的文件扩展名，现在是一个操作
Hello these beautiful people and walk into this video all about file extensions in Linux now an operating
Windows文件扩展名等系统允许您告诉您处理的是哪种类型的文件
system such as Windows file extensions allow you to tell what type of file that you're dealing with
一目了然。
at a glance.
例如，我们知道名称以DR XTi结尾的文件是文本文件，而名称以DR XTi结尾的文件
For example we know that files with names ending in Dr XTi are text files and files with names ending
在Dot中，J-P或PNB很可能是图像在Linux中的字体扩展名，通常与系统无关
in Dot J-P or PNB are likely to be images in Linux font extensions usually don't matter and the system
倾向于查看文件的内容，而不仅仅是它的名称，有时还会真正地查看文件扩展名
tends to look at the contents of the file rather than just its name but sometimes file extensions really
确实很重要。
do matter.
在这段视频中，我们将深入了解Linux中的文件扩展名
So in this video we're going to take a bit of a deep dive into understanding file extensions in Linux
给他们奇怪的行为带来一些光芒。
and shine some light onto their strange behavior.
在视频的最后，您将了解Linux操作系统在命名时为您提供了哪些自由
And by the end of the video you'll know what freedoms the Linux operating system gives you when naming
你的文件。
your files.
可以发生什么有趣的事情，以及你需要注意什么。
What interesting things can happen and what you need to be aware of.
此外，您的工具包中还会有一个新命令，该命令将在处理上的文件时为您提供帮助
And you'll also have a new command in your tool kit that will help you when dealing with files on your
文件系统。
file system.
所以这些都是非常有用的东西，非常令人兴奋的东西。
So this is all very useful stuff very exciting stuff.
让我们直接跳进去吧。
Let's go ahead and jump right into it.
好的，我已经把一些文件放到我的桌面上了。
All right so I've gone ahead and put some files on my desktop.
首先，我这里有一张tuks的图片，这是Linux的传统企鹅徽标，是P和G格式的。
First of all I've got an image of tuks the traditional penguin logo for Linux here in P and G format.
如果你感兴趣的话，现在就说吧，这个词是燕尾服的缩写，是一种奇特的黑色和
Now talks in case you're interested is short for the word tuxedo which is a fancy type of black and
通常是服务员穿的白色西装，可能只有参加高级聚会的人才穿。
white suit usually worn by waiters and possibly just people at high class parties.
据说这些企鹅看起来像是穿着小燕尾服，因为它们的颜色是黑白相间的。
The penguins are said to look like they're wearing little tuxedos because of their black and white coloring.
这就是塔克斯从燕尾服得名的地方。
And that's where tuks gets his name from a tuxedo.
如果你感兴趣，除了这里关于随机琐事的可爱演讲的照片外，我还
In case you were interested but besides a picture of the lovely talks here on random trivia I've also
我这里有一个文本文件，里面有一些莎士比亚作品，叫做莎士比亚文档文本，我还有一个电子表格
got a text file here with some Shakespeare in it called Shakespeare doc text and I also have a spreadsheet
里面有一些随机数字的文件。
file with some random numbers in it.
好的，让我们继续看一下file命令，看看Linux是如何处理文件类型的。
OK so let's go ahead and take a look at the file command to see how Linux handles file types.
因此，如果我继续使用CONTROL ALT反键盘快捷键打开一个终端，并将其拖出
So if I go ahead and open a terminal using the control alt anti keyboard shortcut and just drag it out
这条路让我们还能看到文件。
the way so we can still see the files.
我将向您介绍一个名为file命令的新命令。
I'm going to introduce you to a new command called the file command.
现在，file命令将基本上告诉我们正在处理的是哪种类型的文件。
Now the file command will tell us basically what type of file we are dealing with.
举个例子，如果我们试着看一下这里的TUK。
So for example if we tried to have a look at tuks here.
如果我们做了文件，就在这里停下来，我们实际上把它拿到了我们的桌面上，首先转移到了桌面上。
If we do file took it stop here and we actually took it to our desktop first shift over to a desktop.
清除屏幕并执行文件TUT。
Clear the screen and do file tuks.
实际上只是想让你知道我可以和你在一起。
Actually just just so you see I can actually just with you.
往前走，按Tab键，它也会自动填充，只会向您显示到完工工程的工作台
Go ahead and press tab and it will auto filled as well just showing you the table to completion works
完全适用于文件名，就像适用于文件夹一样，所以这是我们学到的一件很棒的事情
perfectly fine for filenames just like it does for folders so it's a great great thing that we learnt
在最后一段视频中。
in the last video.
好的，让我们看一看谈话的文件，停止DNJ，它会告诉我们这是P，N.G.图像数据。
OK so let's have a look file of talks stop DNJ and it will tell us that this is P N.G. image data.
它将告诉我们文件的大小以及加载的其他内容。
It will tell us the size of the file and loads of other stuff as well.
好的，但是它会告诉我们文件类型。
OK but it tells us the file type.
好的，现在，如果我改名为tok，停止dnj。
OK now if I rename tok stop DNJ.
好的，如果我将其重命名为Take Start JP G。
OK if I rename this to took start JP G.
OK，这是另一种类型的图像文件。
OK which is another type of image file.
你可以看到那里已经改名了，但是我想再来一次。
You can see there's been renamed there but I to do that again.
好的，试一下盘点JP的文件，让我们看看会发生什么。
OK try file of took stock JP and let's see what happens.
现在你可以在这里看到，它仍然说这是一个p和g文件。
Now you can see here that it still says that it is a P and g file.
这一点很重要。
Now this is important.
Linux文件扩展名中的点数1无关紧要。
Point number 1 in linux file extensions don't matter.
好的，与Windows不同，Linux不确定文件类型。
Ok unlike Windows Linux doesn't determine file type.
使用文件扩展名。
Using the file extension.
相反，它读取插入到每个文件顶部的一段代码，这段代码是已知的
But instead it reads a piece of code inserted at the top of every file and that piece of code is known
作为标头，它充当Linux要读取的一种标签，当Linux读取该标签时，它知道
as a header and it serves as a kind of label for Linux to read and when Linux reads that label it knows
文件类型。
the file type.
因此，只更改文件名不会有什么不同，因为文件头不会更改。
So changing just the name of the file won't make a difference because that file header won't have changed.
好的，这里我们有一些文本格式的莎士比亚剧本。
OK so here we have some Shakespeare script in text format.
如果我打开，你可以看到里面有很多我刚刚复制和粘贴的文本
If I open the up you can see that there is plenty of text in there which I just copied and pasted from
罗密欧与朱丽叶。
Romeo and Juliet.
好的，当我们检查这里的文件类型时，如果我们确实将莎士比亚归档，我会这样做
OK so this kind of stuff that I do so when we check the file type we have here if we do file Shakespeare
如果要发送文本，它会告诉我们这是一个ASCII文本文件。
to text it will tell us that it is an ASCII text file.
好的，但是现在，如果我试着把它变成PTF，如果我重命名，然后试着说，好的，这就是莎士比亚。
Ok but now if I try to turn this into a PTF So if I rename it and try to say OK this is now Shakespear.
DOC PTF OK并重命名它。
Doc PTF OK and rename it.
现在，系统似乎已向右更改了图标。
Now the system appears to have changed the icon right.
看起来那是个PDA文件。
It looks like that's a PDA file.
但是如果我再次尝试从命令运行莎士比亚或PTF的文件，它仍然告诉我们它是ASCII
But if I try to run the file from command again for Shakespeare or PTF it still tells us that it's ASCII
文本所以Linux读取了Linux，读取了文件头，发现它仍然是一个文本文件。
text so Linux read the Linux read the header of the file and saw that it was still a text file.
但当我们试图打开它时会发生什么，因为它看起来像是系统认为它是PTF，因为您
But what happens when we try to open it because it looks like the system thinks it's a PTF because you
我可以看到徽标改变了，但它仍然告诉我们这是一个文本文件。
can see the logos changed but it's still telling us it is a text file.
那里发生了什么事。
What's going on there.
为什么它认为如果我们试着打开它会有什么不同。
Why is it think it's different if we try to open it what happens.
现在我们得到了一个。
Well now we get an.
OK是PDA阅读器，它是打开名称以Dot PTF结尾的文件的默认程序。
OK which is the default program to open files with names ending in Dot PTF is a PDA reader.
当我们尝试在PDA阅读器中打开此文件时，程序会出现错误，因为它正在尝试打开
When we try to open this file in the PDA reader we get an error from the program as it's trying to open
我们的文件是PDA文件，系统基本上是说，啊，这是一个以点PTF结尾的文件。
our file is a PDA file and what the system basically did is say ah that's a file that ends in Dot PTF.
很可能是PDA文件。
It's probably a PDA file.
因此，让我提供帮助，并允许用户在PDA查看器中打开它。
So let me be helpful and allow the user to open it in a PDA viewer.
很明显，PDA读取程序不是为读取文本文件而设计的，而是为读取PTF而设计的。
Now obviously a PDA reading program isn't designed to read text files is designed to read PTF.
这就是导致这里问题的原因。
And that's what's causing the issue here.
现在这是重要的，这是一个重要的区别。
Now this is import this is an important distinction to make.
要点二，尽管操作系统将知道实际文件的文件格式
Important point number two although the operating system will know what file format the actual file
就是通过读取标题。
is by reading the header.
安装在操作系统顶部的额外程序(如此PDA查看器)正在尝试
The extra programs that are installed on top of the operating system such as this PDA viewer are trying
若要打开可能需要特定格式或文件扩展名才能工作的文件，请执行以下操作。
to open the files that might require a certain formats or the file extensions in order to work.
这是怎么回事，这一切都是为了让它自动打开，你想把它作为PDA打开，它刚刚看到
So what's happening is it all this to make this automatic you want to open as a PDA it just saw the
文件名它只看了文件名，但内容仍然是文本。
file name it just looked at the file name but the content is still text.
它说这里有一种文件类型，不支持纯文本，但它让程序上当了，它看到了
And it says here are a file type plain text is not supported but it got the program got tricked it saw
文件名，这就是它想要将其作为PDA打开的原因。
the file name and that's why it wanted to open it as a PDA.
如果我将其重命名为Text，只需将文本改回即可。
If I rename it back to text just change the text change back.
现在您将看到它将作为文本文件正常打开。
You'll see now that it will open fine as a text file.
好的，这是使安装在操作之上的程序存在的重要区别
OK so that's the important distinction to make there the programs that are installed on top of the operating
系统(如PDA视图)以及它们可能需要文件具有特定文件扩展名的事实
system such as PDA views and the fact that they might need the file to have a specific file extension
才能打开它们。
in order to open them.
但是操作系统本身并不关心。
But the operating system itself does not care.
如果我看一下这里的电子表格，这是一个更详细的信息。
So this is a bit more detail if I take a look at the spreadsheet here.
它被称为数据O.D.，就好像我做的数据文件那样令人讨厌。
It's called data O.D. as if I do file of data that odious.
好的。
OK.
它说这是一个令人讨厌的转账开放文档电子表格。
It says that it's an odious forward transfer open document spreadsheet.
好的。
OK.
现在，这意味着我们可以在Libra office calc中打开它，它基本上是Microsoft的Linux版本
Now this means we can open it up in Libris office calc which is basically the Linux version of Microsoft
Excel。
Excel.
好的，所有苹果的等价物都类似于电子表格程序。
OK all the Apple equivalent is like the spreadsheet program.
好的。
OK.
里面有几个数字。
And it's got it's got a few numbers in there.
好的。
OK.
但是如果我关闭电子表格并重命名，例如采用Ex-Sea文件。
But if I close the spreadsheet and rename that for example to adopt Ex-Sea file.
好的。
OK.
因此，如果我将其重命名为Data RTX，则将其重命名。
So if I rename it to data RTX to rename that.
好的，您可以看到，现在它想要以成人文本格式打开。
OK you can see that now it wants to be opened up in adult text format.
好的。
OK.
现在我尝试在Libra office calc中打开它，所以如果我单击此处，我键入calc，它就会出现
And now I tried to open that up in Libris office calc so if I click here I type calc and it comes up
天秤座是卡尔。
Libra is calc.
等它启动。
Wait for that to boot up.
文件打开转到我的桌面，即主页，然后转到桌面，然后尝试打开Data腾讯日，您可以
File Open go to my desktop so home and then desktop and then try to open up data RTX day and you can
现在你看，我们这里发生了各种各样的问题。
see now that we've got all kinds of problems happening here.
好的，如果我试着像这样打开它，强烈的点击OK。
OK so if I try to just open it like that a strong click OK.
我们会收到一个错误。
We're going to get an error.
好的。
OK.
这是因为DOT TXI文件扩展名愚弄了LIBRIS OFFICE CLAQUE LIBRAD OFFICE CALQUE
And this is because the DOT TXI file extension is fooling Libris office calque libral office calque
犯了读取文件扩展名并尝试将文件作为点打开的错误。
made the mistake of reading the file extension and trying to open the file as a dot.
t x t文件。
T x t file.
好的。
OK.
这里是实际内容，我们可以看到，这里是一个电子表格文件，而不是文本文件。
Where is the actual content as we can see here is a spreadsheet file it's not a text file.
好的，但是如果我们把它重新命名，我们把它重新命名，这样它就有日期了。
Ok but if we rename that back and we rename it so that it's dated.
是。
Yes.
现在它会开得很好。
Now it will open fine.
因此，这是我们需要进行的重要区分，并强调文件扩展名
So this is the important distinction that we need to make and to hammer this home the file extension
对于Linux操作系统来说并不重要，但是对于
isn't important to the Linux operating system but it might be important to the software packages that
我们安装在Linux之上。
we install on top of Linux.
所以请记住，基本上不要给你的文件名提供非常奇怪的文件扩展名
So do bear in mind that don't basically don't give your file names really weird file extensions that
与其内容不匹配，因为这可能会混淆安装正常的第三方软件
don't match their content because it might confuse third party software that is installed OK even though
你不一定非得这么做。
you don't necessarily have to.
好的，那么让我们给这个电子表格一个完全未知的东西，尝试一下其他的东西。
OK so let's give the spreadsheet a completely unknown try something else.
这是一件相当有趣的事情。
This is something quite interesting.
让我们给电子表格一个完全虚构的文件扩展名。
Let's give the spreadsheet a completely made up file extensions.
如果我把它叫做电子表格点香巴拉，好的，我会把它叫做电子表格数据之类的。
If I call it spreadsheet dot Shambhala OK I'll call it spreadsheet datcha blah.
那真是太有趣了。
That was interesting.
注意它是如何自动地仍然想要在电子表格软件中打开它的。
Notice how it automatically still wants to open it up in the spreadsheet software.
现在我们在这里注意到，我们没有欺骗软件，它仍然知道这是一个令人讨厌的文件，并且
Now we notice here that we didn't fool the the the software and it still knows it's an odious file and
我们实际上可以打开它，只要我继续双击，它就会完全打开。
we can actually open it up if I just go ahead and double click the it's going to open up perfectly fine.
你看，我们这里有我们的数据。
You see we've got our data in here.
这次可不是闹着玩的。
No funny business this time.
那么，为什么这个系统可以，为什么它不能打开一个奇怪的文件名，而不是像Dotti XTi这样简单的文件名。
So why can this system why can it open up a weird file name but not a simple one like Dotti XTi.
原因是软件根本无法识别荷兰语pablum文件扩展名，所以它可能
Well the reason is the software just simply didn't recognize the Dutch pablum file extension so it might
而是求助于操作系统来帮助确定文件类型。
have looked to the operating system to help determine the file type instead.
但是当我们称它为Datti XTi文件时，嗯。
But when we called it a Datti XTi file huh.
当我们实际将其直接命名为Datti XTi时，软件认为它会有点聪明
When we actually named it directly to be Datti XTi the software thought it would be a bit clever and
它想，啊哈，我知道怎么处理这件事，它给自己开了一条捷径，而且是
it thought aha I know how to deal with this and it made a little bit of a shortcut to itself and was
就像我会自动把它作为文本文件打开一样。
like I'm just going to open this automatically as a text file.
但在这种情况下，这种假设是错误的，因为内容是电子表格。
But that assumption was wrong in this case because the content is a spreadsheet.
我们只是将其命名为Dotty XTi，这导致程序在发现它不是Dotty XTi时抛出一个错误
We just named it Dotty XTi and that caused the program to throw an error when it found out it wasn't
毕竟是文本文件，但实际上是电子表格。
a text file after all but actually was a spreadsheet.
底线是在Linux中有很大的自由来命名文件，您甚至可以将其称为
The bottom line is have a lot of freedom to name files what ever you want in Linux you can even call
他们。
them.
您甚至可以为他们提供文件扩展名，如Dot shoeBlack。
You can even give them file extensions like Dot shoeblack.
当然，这在任何其他操作系统中都做不到。
Which of course you couldn't do in any other operating system.
这对于拥有文件来说是很常见的。
This is common for having files.
例如，如果我只是尝试复制并粘贴此文件，如果我复制并粘贴此文件，您知道您可能会有
For example if I just try and copy and paste this if I copy and paste this file you know you might have
一个后备。
a backup.
例如，您可以将1个文件称为原始文件，因此您会说，好的，我将把这个点称为山脊
You might for example call 1 file an original So you'd say OK I'm going to call this one dot a ridge
然后我会给这个打个电话。
and then I'd call this one.
也许我会把一个点打回来，或者你知道一份复印件，叫它点复印件或类似的东西
Maybe I'll call in the one dot back or you know a copy and call it dot dot dot copy or something like
那。
that.
好的，您可以这样命名您的文件。
OK and this is how you might name your files.
我相信这是原件，这是我只看文件名就能看到的副本，实际上并没有
I believe this is the original this is the copy I can see just by looking at the file name without actually
影响系统的运作方式。
affecting the way the system works.
因此，这有时被用来允许人们读取更具人类可读性的文件扩展名
So this is sometimes used to allow people to read file extensions that are a lot more human readable
而不是你知道的像点恶心或点之类的东西。
than you know things like dot odious or dot whatever.
好的，但是请确保，如果您以这种方式命名文件，请不要为它们指定可能
Ok but just make sure that if you name your files in such a way don't give them file names that might
混淆你期望打开它们的软件，因为并不是所有的软件都喜欢与陌生的软件打交道
confuse the software that you expect to open them because not all softwares like to play ball with strange
文件名。
file names.
好了，关于Linux文件扩展名的讨论到此为止。
OK so that will bring a discussion of Linux file extensions to a close.
这是你在这段视频中学到的内容的总结。
So it's a summary of what you learn in this video.
您将了解到，您可以使用FILE命令来确定您正在处理的是哪种类型的文件。
You learn that you can use the file command to know for sure what type of file that you're dealing with.
或者您知道文件扩展名对Linux操作系统并不重要，这意味着您可以
Or you know that file extensions aren't important to the Linux operating system which means you can
随你怎么命名文件。
name files whatever you want.
是的，甚至是DOT鞋黑。
Yes even DOT shoeblack.
但当您这样做时，请确保不要混淆第三方软件，这些软件可能需要
But while you're doing that make sure you try not to confuse third party software that might need to
打开该文件，因为它可能需要特定的文件扩展名。
open the file because it might be expecting specific file extensions.
如果你试图混淆它，那么你知道你只会在一个非常非常糟糕的时候得到错误。
And if you try to confuse it then you know you'll just get errors in a very very bad time.
接下来，在下一个视频中，我们将把您的命令行技能提升到一个全新的水平
So coming up next in the next video we're going to take your command line skills to a whole new level
通过观察通配符的概念。
by looking at the concept of wild cards.
假设您有一个非常杂乱的桌面，您想要将所有图像移动到一个文件夹中
So let's say you had a really messy desktop and you wanted to move all of your images to one folder
您的所有PDA都放到一个文件夹中，而您所有的电子表格和办公室都在该文件夹下
and all of your PDA to one or the folder and all of your spreadsheets and office falls under the folder
使用命令行。
using the command line.
你怎么能使用一个如此具体的命令。
How can you use a command that's actually so specific.
您可以使用通配符来实现这一点。
Well you can do that using wildcards.
通配符允许您将命令变得非常具体，也非常通用，从而允许
Wildcards allow you to make your commands really really specific and also really general thereby allowing
您需要提高对实际操作的命令的控制级别。
you to level up your control over what commands actually operate on.
在处理文件时，这是一种非常有用的能力，再来看看史诗超级大国的另一剂
Now this is an incredibly useful ability when dealing with files so for another dose of epic superpower's
我将在下一个视频中见到你。
I'll see you in the next video.